buttonpoetry.com 2019-03-27

# Button Poetry Privacy Policy - Button Poetry

## The short version

> ### GDPR Note
> 
> We are in the process of updating our website policies and procedures in conjunction with GDPR. As a small, US-based company, we are striving to better serve our EU visitors and customers. If you have any specific concerns about our website in this regard, please contact us at support@buttonpoetry.com and we will do our best to resolve them swiftly.
> 
> For now, please know that to help poets reach a wide audience we use industry-standard tracking scripts from Google and Facebook. We also use some on-site cookies to operate our online shop and ask for information to process orders and respond to inquiries.

Below we have a more technical policy to meet legal requirements, but the gist is this: to do business on the internet Button Poetry uses cookies on our website, which makes our online shopping cart function and lets us see how people use the website so we can keep improving it. We also collect information about your visit and directly from you when you place orders or sign up to our newsletter. We also have ads, and once you click on an ad and leave our website our privacy policy no longer applies. We do not share your personal information with others, and protect what information you share with us as if it was our own.

* * *

This privacy policy is an evolving document and has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally Identifiable Information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as described in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your PII in accordance with our website.

## Who We Are

Button Poetry is committed to developing a coherent and effective system of production, distribution, promotion and fundraising for performance poetry. Buttonpoetry.com is owned and operated by Button Publishing, Inc., a US company operating out of Minneapolis, MN. For more about button, visit our [About us](https://buttonpoetry.com/about-us/) page.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments and Reviews

When visitors leave comments or reviews on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Contact and subscription forms

When visitors fill out a form, we collect their names and email addresses needed to reply to queries or, dependent on the clearly stated purpose of the form, subscribe them to our mailing lists and any related promotions.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

When you close our Privacy Policy pop-up, an anonymous cookie is stored on your device to prevent the popup from re-appearing for a 30-day period. This cookie is designed to prevent a repetitive browsing experience and for no other purpose. We also anonymously tracks popup views.

Some of our third-party services also set cookies. To learn about these services read the ‘What we share with others’ section of this policy.

### Embedded content from other websites

Pages on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

In particular, our video pages embed YouTube videos, and some pages feature a sidebar embeds a Bandcamp audio player and Eventbrite embed. You can visit these sites’ privacy policies here:

  * YouTube (Google): <https://policies.google.com/privacy>
  * Bandcamp: <https://bandcamp.com/privacy>
  * Eventbrite: <https://www.eventbrite.com/support/articles/en_US/Troubleshooting/eventbrite-privacy-policy?lg=en_US>

### Web Store Policies

While you visit our web store and product pages, we’ll track:

  * Products you’ve viewed: we’ll use this to, for example, show you products you’ve recently viewed
  * Location, IP address and browser type: we’ll use this for purposes like estimating taxes and shipping
  * Shipping address: we’ll ask you to enter this so we can, for instance, estimate shipping before you place an order, and send you the order!

We’ll also use cookies to keep track of cart contents while you’re browsing our site.

When you purchase from us, we’ll ask you to provide information including your name, billing address, shipping address, email address, phone number, credit card/payment details and optional account information like username and password. We’ll use this information for purposes, such as, to:

  * Send you information about your account and order
  * Respond to your requests, including refunds and complaints
  * Add you to our mailing list, if you checked the opt-in to do so
  * Process payments and prevent fraud
  * Set up your account for our store
  * Comply with any legal obligations we have, such as calculating taxes
  * Improve our store offerings
  * Send you marketing messages, if you choose to receive them

## Who on our team has access.

Members of our team have access to the information you provide us. For example, both Administrators and Shop Managers can access:

  * Order information like what was purchased, when it was purchased and where it should be sent, and
  * Customer information like your name, email address, and billing and shipping information.

Our team members have access to this information to help fulfill orders, process refunds and support you.

## What we share with others / Where we send your data

### Marketing Analytics

On behalf of our authors, we use industry standard marketing and analytics techniques provided by Google and Facebook. Here is a summary of those and their privacy policies:

  * Google Analytics and Adwords: We insert Google’s scripts to display ads and collect site usage statistics. Google collects IP addresses to help us understand where visitors are coming from, which pages they view, and how long they visit for. These data are stored and processed on Google’s servers. You can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the [Google Ad Settings page](https://adssettings.google.com/). Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/) page or by using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on. You can view Google’s privacy policy at: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>
  * Facebook Pixel: We insert Facebook’s scripts which help us measure conversions from Facebook ads to our products. This can include information such as your IP address and anonymized demographic and location information to help us understand our audience. You can view Facebook’s privacy policy at: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy>

Outside of marketing and site usage statistics, we do not share your data except in instances necessary to do our business, such as providing names and addresses to shipping providers for delivering physical goods. We do not provide such third party any permissions to use or retain such data outside of the scope of fulfilling your order or supporting you.

### Payments

We accept payments through PayPal and by Credit Card via our credit card processor, Authorize.net. When processing payments, some of your data will be passed to Authorize.net or Paypal depending on your chosen payment, including information required to process or support the payment, such as the purchase total and billing information.

Please see the [Authorize.net Privacy Policy](https://www.authorize.net/company/privacy/) and [PayPal Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) for more details.

## How long we retain your data

We generally store information about you for as long as we need the information for the purposes for which we collect and use it, and we are not legally required to continue to keep it. For example, we will store order information for at least 7 years for tax and accounting purposes following industry recommendations. This includes your name, email address and billing and shipping addresses.

If you leave a comment or review, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For customers that register on our website, we will store your name, address, email and phone number, which will be used to populate the checkout for future orders. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Your contact information

For any inquiries about your privacy on our website, please email [support@buttonpoetry.com](mailto:support@buttonpoetry.com).

## Additional information

### How we protect your data

Button Poetry staff take your privacy very seriously, and never share your data outside of the company except where it is required to fulfill orders and provide support you ask for. We use secure company email addresses, have premium secure web hosting, and keep our technologies up to date to lower the chance of a breach or exposure of customer’s private data.

### What data breach procedures we have in place

In the unlikely event of a data breach we will report the breach and announce any theft of data with all relevant information on our website, our social media channels such as Facebook, and through our opt-in mailing lists. We will disclose, unless advised otherwise by law enforcement, what kind of information was lost and to whom.
